<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Robert Marty</title>
    <link>https://ramarty.github.io/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Robert Marty</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ramarty.github.io/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the causal impact of Chinese aid on vegetative land cover in Burundi and Rwanda under conditions of spatial imprecision</title>
      <link>https://ramarty.github.io/publications/geosimex/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramarty.github.io/publications/geosimex/</guid>
      <description>There has been considerable debate regarding the efficacy of international aid in meeting the dual goals of human development and environmental sustainability. Many donors have sought to engage with this challenge by introducing environmental safeguard and monitoring initiatives; however, evidence on the success of these interventions is limited. Evaluating aid is a particular challenge in the case of donors that do not disclose information on the nature, geographic location, or extents of their interventions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of aid on health outcomes in Uganda</title>
      <link>https://ramarty.github.io/publications/ugandahealthaid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramarty.github.io/publications/ugandahealthaid/</guid>
      <description>The health sector has attracted significant foreign aid; however, evidence on the effectiveness of this support is mixed. This paper combines household panel data with geographically referenced subnational foreign aid data to investigate the contribution of health aid to health outcomes in Uganda. Using a difference-in-differences approach, we find that aid had a strong effect on reducing the productivity burden of disease indicated by days of productivity lost due to illness but was less effective in reducing disease prevalence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Top-Down Approach to Estimating Spatially Heterogeneous Impacts of Development Aid on Vegetative Carbon Sequestration</title>
      <link>https://ramarty.github.io/publications/carbonsequestration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramarty.github.io/publications/carbonsequestration/</guid>
      <description>Since 1945, over $4.9 trillion dollars of international aid has been allocated to developing countries. To date, there have been no estimates of the regional impact of this aid on the carbon cycle. We apply a geographically explicit matching method to estimate the relative impact of large-scale World Bank projects implemented between 2000 and 2010 on sequestered carbon, using a novel and publicly available data set of 61,243 World Bank project locations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking the health aid debate to the subnational level: the impact and allocation of foreign health aid in Malawi</title>
      <link>https://ramarty.github.io/publications/malawihealthaid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramarty.github.io/publications/malawihealthaid/</guid>
      <description>Objective: Cross-national studies provide inconclusive results as to the effectiveness of foreign health aid. We highlight a novel application of using subnational data to evaluate aid impacts, using Malawi as a case study.
Design: We employ two rounds of nationally representative household surveys (2004&amp;frasl;2005 and 2010&amp;frasl;2011) and geo-referenced foreign aid data. We examine the determinants of Malawi&amp;rsquo;s traditional authorities receiving aid according to health, environmental risk, socioeconomic and political factors. We use two approaches to estimate the impact of aid on reducing malaria prevalence and increasing healthcare quality: difference-in-difference models, which include traditional authority and month-of-interview fixed effects and control for individual and household level time-varying factors, and entropy balancing, where models balance on health-related and socioeconomic baseline characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Survival Analysis of Regional Unemployment in Uganda: Evidence from the Uganda National Panel Survey (UNPS)</title>
      <link>https://ramarty.github.io/publications/ugandasurvivalanalysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramarty.github.io/publications/ugandasurvivalanalysis/</guid>
      <description>The study utilizes survival analysis methodology to examine unemployment duration in Uganda’s five regions. The analysis is developed on a database of cohorts of the Uganda National Household Survey (UNHS) for the year 2005&amp;frasl;06 and the Uganda National Panel Survey (UNPS) for the years 2009&amp;frasl;10, 2010&amp;frasl;11 and 2011&amp;frasl;12. This work analyses individuals’ first spell of unemployment using the Kaplan Meier estimator of the survival functions in unemployment and the covariate effects on duration using the Cox Proportional Hazard Model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Conceptual and Methodological Foundations in Community Engagement</title>
      <link>https://ramarty.github.io/publications/somos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramarty.github.io/publications/somos/</guid>
      <description>We describe the efforts of two related undergraduate projects to promote lasting social change in marginalized communities in the Dominican Republic and Nicaragua. The projects represent a test of the premise that undergraduate projects can engage academically based strategies and transcend good intentions to achieve effective community partnerships to improve health and health care. The projects proceed from a perspective and theory of marginalization and its consequences. Specifically, marginalization undermines individual and collective capacity to meet basic needs and efforts to thrive.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>